Allamaneni Dheeraj

IOT DEVELOPER · ALENTHUSIAST

4122 Harris st, Ames, Iowa

🛮 (+1) 646-384-3078 | 🗷 dheeraj@iastate.edu | 🏕 www.dheeraj.live | 🖸 dheeraj-allamaneni | 🛅 dheerajallamaneni

"Willingness to fail is opportunity to innovate."

Summary_

Master's student in Computer Engineering - Actively seeking an Internship/Co-op position for the upcoming Summer. Past IoT Developer at start-up company PARISHOD Tech. 1-year experience specializing in Robotics, IoT, and backend. Interested in devising a better problem-solving strategy for challenging tasks, Deep Learning dev and specifically interested working on Self-driving car's.

Work Experience _____

Iowa State University.

GRADUATE RESEARCH ASSISTANT

· Working under guidance of Dr.Yu Wang on Energy Modeling.

PARISHOD Tech.

T.Hub, Hyderabad

 IOT DEVELOPER
 Jun. 2017 - DEC. 2017

T.Hub, Hyderabad

Jun. 2018 - PRESENT

Jan. 2015 - Apr. 2015

Microsoft Campus

• Leading a Team of seven, Developed and built intelligent robots and IoT Products.

• Major projects include Agriculture automation for Mahindra Rise and Medical vending machine (IoT).

INSIGNIA Labs. Hyderabad, INDIA

RESEARCH INTERN

- Developed long range wireless power transfer system.
- Developed games with Arduino and Raspberry pi.
- Implemented pezio electric power generation.

Honors & Awards

INTERNATIONAL

Jun. 2017	1st Place, AngelHack.	India
		mulu
Apr. 2017	Finalist , Smart India Hackathon under Department of Defense Production by Government of India . This	Bangalore, India
	whole project was demonstrated to Honorable PM Narendra Modi sir and has appreciated for our efforts.	Barryarore, mara
Sep. 2016	3rd Place , Megathon (A 24Hrs hackathon) by E-Cell IIT-Hyd and IIIT-Hyd	T.Hub, India
Nov. 2016	Finalist , Showcased our IoT product Medicine-Reminder to Steve Crocker Chair, ICANN Board of Directors at	Hyderabad, India
1100. 2010	CANN57(18th AGM)	
Mar. 2016	4th Place, International Autonomous Robotics Competition at IIT-Kanpur	Kanpur, India
Dec. 2015	2nd Place, International Robotics Competition at IIT-Bombay	Mumbai, India
Oct. 2011	Distinction , Australian National Chemistry Quiz by ROYAL AUSTRALIAN CHEMICAL INSTITUTE	New Delhi, India

DOMESTIC

Mar. 2016 1st Place , Autonomous Robotics at JNTUH	India
Mar. 2016 1st Place, Maze Solver (Robotics competition) at CVR College of Engineering	India
Apr. 2016 2nd Place , Project expo at Mahatma Gandhi Institute of Technology	India
Feb. 2016 1st Place , Robotics Competition Conducted by SAKSHI-ARENAONE Youth-fest	India
Feb. 2016 Silver Medal, Best performance in Electronic design projects at Mallareddy college of Engineering	India
Jan. 2016 Finalist , DTMF Race at IIT-Hyderabad	India
Sep. 2015 1st Place, Robotics Competition at FACEit-2K15(A NATIONAL LEVEL TECHNICAL SYMPOSIUM)	India
Jun. 2015 2nd Place , Group Discussion at Anushthana-2K14 (Annual Cultural fest at ACE)	India

Presentation

IEEE Paperpresentation at Osmania University

WATER QUALITY MONITORING USING REMOTE SENSING AND NEURAL NETWORKS

Hyderabad, India

Mar. 2015

IEEE Paperpresentation at Mahatma Gandhi Institute of Technology

Hyderabad, India

SWARM ROBOTICS Mar. 2015

Technical Skills

Programming Languages, : C, R, MATLAB, Wolfram Mathematica

Libraries, : Tensorflow, Keras, NumPy Scripting, : Python, JavaScript HPC using, : MPI, Open MP

Tools Used,: MATLAB R2015a, Mathematica, IBM Bluemix, Xilinx ISE, NI-LabVIEW and Multisim

HDL S,: VHDL, Verilog

Markup Languages, : HTML5, LaTeX

Education

Iowa State University

Ames, Iowa

MS-THESIS IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

Jan. 2018 - Jan. 2020

• Rocket Shop I along with my team are working on Avionics of "INVICTUS" a 12' 7" rocket, which aims to reach the 30,000ft mark with our team built SRAD Propulsion motor for "Spaceport America Cup"; where we(Avionics) primarily handle all the sensors data and implement necessary actions like deploying Air Breaks, Transmitting the Telemetry data to the ground station, Analyzing the path of our Rocket and also helping in locating the rocket at Recovery stage.

ACE Engineering College Hyderabad, India

B.Tech. IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING

Mar. 2013 - Jun. 2017

- Graduated with "First Class"
- · Major Project: RoadTrack AI based Real time Road quality measurement and mapping with route planning.
- Mini Project: Tracking Beacon Cloud based Real time GPS tracking with Time of Arrival Estimation.

DELTA Junior college

Hyderabad, India

INTERMEDIATE EDUCATION IN MATHEMATICS, PHYSICS AND CHEMISTRY

• Percentage: **82.5%**

Certifications

Self-DrivingCar Engineer Nanodegree Program

UDACITY Aug. 2018

Neural Networks and Deep Learning

Coursera Sep. 2018

HTML, CSS, and Javascript for Web Developers

JOHNS HOPKINS UNIVERSITY Feb. 2017 - Apr. 2017

Machine Learning

STANFORD UNIVERSITY Dec. 2016

Digital Circuits and Systems

IIT-Madras Apr. 2015

Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms

IIT-Madras Jul. 2014